# Roman Resenchuk



r@resrom.com



+14843063572



linkedin.com/in/romanres



https://resrom.com

### Summary

Software engineer, IT entrepreneur, manager.

Since 2011 to the present, I have been developing iOS applications.

I can coordinate teamwork to develop high-quality projects, consult the clients and the team, or take the project as an independent work, using best practices in code writing.

Working with me, you'll get:

- responsible attitude;
- understanding and politeness in communication;
- efficiency and compliance;

My hobbies: IT, computers, cars, motorcycles, finances, cryptocurrency, travel and exploration.

### **Experience**



#### Software Engineer, IT entrepreneur, Manager

Self-Employed

Jul 2021 - Mar 2022 (9 months)

During this time I was engaged in the development of my own projects, working with designers, marketing partners, promotion in the AppStore, investing own money in business. Also, I was actively studying and catching up on lost knowledge in programming with the latest technologies, learned SwiftUI, released an application developed from scratch on it.

Released several applications to the AppStore with subscription monetization:

- "MathBrain - Math Games": https://apple.co/3D4IDX6

Others: "Brain Gym", "2FA Authenticator", "ConnectSpeaker"

#### iOS Team Lead

#### MyNovel

Jul 2021 - Nov 2021 (5 months)

Starting from scratch, I joined the startup as a lead iOS developer, created the foundation application code on the CleanSwift architecture, creating high-quality and supported code and an perfect adaptive UI layout. There were 3 iOS programmers in the team, I coordinated their work, did a code review, managed a set of tasks, and also worked with the analytics/advertising/user engagement sections. Working together, we implemented many complex functions and completed the project in very good condition, which we can be proud of.

- "MyNovel: Novels & Stories" https://apple.co/3a49jg1



#### iOS Developer

Tapcentive, Inc.

Jun 2019 - Jul 2021 (2 years 2 months)

I have worked with NFC and Chip card related applications. Participated in the development of the project as part of a professional and talented team. My responsibilities included developing an iOS app from scratch to release and supporting.

Released iOS apps projects:

- "Smart Chip Gaming" (Private AppStore distribution)

Tablet Gaming engine in NFC chip card. App combine the card with an iPad tablet to create the ultimate low cost, high reliability, high security on-property gaming device. Project scope of use is offline casino halls, cruise ships.

- "SmartScratch Helper" https://apple.co/30MXDX0

Instant Ticket Gaming. It's a NFC chip card with instant tickets securely stored in the chip. Purchase the card and then tap it with your phone to experience digital fun and find out what you've won.

### Katalyst iOS Developer

#### Katalyst

Jun 2018 - Jan 2020 (1 year 8 months)

Development software in a team, support and launch unique product in Live for a POS terminal in the cloud in the role of using an iPad application to help manage restaurant.

In colaboration with other developers, we developed an iPad application and create a module for working with external hardware devices.

- iOS app "Katalyst Point of Sale" https://apple.co/3zLqrSC

# flyp iOS Developer

#### Flyp

Mar 2017 - Aug 2019 (2 years 6 months)

Development and support of several iOS applications, including legacy modules on Objective C. Stability support and adding new features to applications. Development of new applications in Swift with white-label based on an existing product.

Released iOS apps:

- "Flyp" https://apple.co/39x4ADH

Others: "Solo", "Flex"

# Software Engineer, Designer, Manager.

#### Self-Employed

Nov 2015 - Mar 2017 (1 year 5 months)

Software development: Mobile, iOS, Android applications, UI UX design, developing own projects, preparation of technical documentation, project management.

Mobile applications developments management, clients consulting.

Released several iOS applications: (Objective C, Swift)

- "AUTO.rent" https://apple.co/3aVF7UL

Others: "tip n trip", "Progressio", "Zones", "Star Way Horoscopes (UI/UX, API, Android app)", "FuelHunt

- Map of gas stations",

"Sockets offline map" - Hit the top paid apps in the category, have published popular Russian Internet edition (vc.ru, macdigger, iphones.ru)

# iO:

#### iOS Developer

#### Tinkoff

Aug 2015 - Nov 2015 (4 months)

Developing and support iOS application for payment road traffic fines. The application is part of the ecosystem of one of the largest banks in Russia.

- iOS app "Traffic fines GIBDD"

# пеомоно іО

#### iOS Team Lead

Technopoisk, LLC

Nov 2014 - Aug 2015 (10 months)

Project for smart home control Ready For Sky (R4S).

Work in a team to support and develop new iOS app features. Architectural fixes and improvements directed towards scalability and enhance the prestige of the project. Wiki-documentation. Coordination of work teams. Got a lot of work experience in Agile methodology/Scrum, GitFlow, DevOps.

- iOS app ReadyForSky https://apple.co/3OmrNY1

### iOS Developer

#### Легион

Jul 2013 - Sep 2014 (1 year 3 months)

Independent development of several applications from scratch and support, consultation with agency customers, management and coordination of technical issues, working with the development team (Developers, UI/UX designers, QA engineers), bug tracking systems, development of new startup project. My first experience of remote full-time work with constant communication.

Released iOS apps:

"Bileter.ru", "Vkino.ru Cinemates", "Algeron", "Vmeste app"

# Dotnet Developer

#### **FRESHOFFICE**

Nov 2011 - May 2013 (1 year 7 months)

Participation in the development web site, client web application services and first version of iOS application FreshOffice CRM

# Web Developer

#### Self-Employed

Jun 2009 - Nov 2011 (2 years 6 months)

Web applications, websites and services, developing own projects.

- Web-Sites
- Server REST API
- Web-Applications, Databases
- Game/Entertainment app for Social Networks (Facebook, VK iframe)

#### **Education**

# ITMO University

Information Technology

#### **Skills**

iOS • Swift (Programming Language) • Objective-C • SwiftUI • UIKit • Model-View-Controller (MVC)

· Model-view-viewmodel (MVVM) · Clean Architecture · VIPER · Agile Methodologies